<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Post on John Kane</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Post on John Kane</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Round by Round Seed Combinations in the Men&#39;s NCAA Tournament</title>
      <link>/post/round-by-round-seed-combinations-in-mens-ncaa-tournament/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/round-by-round-seed-combinations-in-mens-ncaa-tournament/</guid>
      <description>Most years filling out my NCAA Tournament bracket I work forwards through the games. I select the winners of the first round games then, using an ever dwindling pool of teams, proceed all the way through to selecting a champion. The later round games are worth more points in bracket pools so you can really hinder your prospects of winning if you don’t at least have an eye on the later rounds of the tournament early on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing Gradient Boosting Decision Trees for Classification</title>
      <link>/post/visualizing-gradient-boosting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/visualizing-gradient-boosting/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Ensemble methods (random forests, gradient boosting machines) have proven to be a winning strategy on Kaggle1. The building blocks of those methods are decision trees, which are generally well understood. It can seem, however, that the ensembling of many trees can produce a sort of magic that allows it to achieve much better performance than a single tree.
When learning about these methods the discussion moves quickly from declaring them an ensemble of trees into a discussion of hyperparameter tuning, glossing over exactly how or why boosting works so well.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>