<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on John Kane</title>
    <link>/tags/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on John Kane</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Round by Round Seed Combinations in the Men&#39;s NCAA Tournament</title>
      <link>/blog/round-by-round-seed-combinations-in-mens-ncaa-tournament/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/round-by-round-seed-combinations-in-mens-ncaa-tournament/</guid>
      <description>Most years filling out my NCAA Tournament bracket I work forwards through the games. I select the winners of the first round games then, using an ever dwindling pool of teams, proceed all the way through to selecting a champion. The later round games are worth more points in bracket pools so you can really hinder your prospects of winning if you don’t at least have an eye on the later rounds of the tournament early on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Round by Round Seed Combinations in the Men&#39;s NCAA Tournament</title>
      <link>/post/round-by-round-seed-combinations-in-mens-ncaa-tournament/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/round-by-round-seed-combinations-in-mens-ncaa-tournament/</guid>
      <description>Most years filling out my NCAA Tournament bracket I work forwards through the games. I select the winners of the first round games then, using an ever dwindling pool of teams, proceed all the way through to selecting a champion. The later round games are worth more points in bracket pools so you can really hinder your prospects of winning if you don’t at least have an eye on the later rounds of the tournament early on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NCAA Men&#39;s Tournament First Round Upsets</title>
      <link>/blog/ncaa-first-round-upsets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/ncaa-first-round-upsets/</guid>
      <description>Unless you follow mid-major conferences closely, when it comes time to picking first round upsets in the NCAA Tournament you’re likely either picking teams at random, or going off the analysis of the “experts” on TV, the internet, or podcasts. I won’t address those who pick their upsets and Cinderella teams at random here, instead this post is about those who combine whatever they know about the field in a given year with what they see, read, and hear in the media.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Functions and Environments</title>
      <link>/blog/functions-and-environments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/functions-and-environments/</guid>
      <description>The content of this post nearly became a Stack Overflow question. In the process of going about making a reproducible example I solved the problem, as often happens. It took a bit of time to stich together several other SO posts before I arrived at it. Hopefully when someone else comes across the issue maybe this will provide some immediate assistance.
The following is the reprex I went about writing to include in the Stack Overflow post.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>